So, what is iteration?
ما المقصود بالتكرار؟
Probably the best way to describe it is by looking at a normal for loop.
ربما تكون الطريقة الأفضل لوصف هذا أن نلقي نظرة على تكرار حلقي "for" عادي.
When you write a for loop,
عند كتابة تكرار حلقي "for"،
you provide the loop with a variable.
فإنكم تزوّدون التكرار الحلقي بمتغير.
This variable is typically the letter I because it's being
ويتمثل هذا المتغير عادةً في الحرف I
used as an iterator to keep track of your place in the loop.
نظرًا لاستخدامه بصفته مُكرِّرًا لتتبع مكانك في التكرار الحلقي.
When you're looping over something like an array,
عند استخدامكم تكرارًا حلقيًا في شيء ما مثل مصفوفة،
this iterator works like an index,
يعمل هذا المُكرِّر مثل فهرس،
letting you access each item in the array one after the other.
ما يُتيح لكم الوصول إلى جميع عناصر المصفوفة واحدًا تلو الآخر.
This process of getting the next item,
وعملية الحصول على العنصر التالي هذه،
one after the other, is iteration,
واحدًا تلو الآخر، هي التكرار.
and we've been using it for a long time.
وقد استخدمناه لفترة طويلة.
So, why even bring this up?
ما سبب نشأته؟
It sounds like iteration has always been a part of Javascript.
يبدو أن التكرار ظل دائمًا جزءًا من لغة Javascript.
So, what's new in ES6?
ما الجديد في ES6؟
Well, there are a couple of things.
حسنًا، يتضمن شيآن جديدان.
First, there's a new iterable interface that
أولهما، وجود واجهة جديدة قابلة للتكرار
allows us to customize how objects are iterated.
تُتيح لنا تخصيص كيفية تكرار الكائنات.
So, basically how they're looped over.
وطريقة تكرارها الحلقي في الأساس.
We'll look at this more closely in lesson three,
سنتناول هذا الموضوع بعمق في الدرس الثالث،
when we talk about symbols.
عندما نتحدث عن الرموز.
The second thing is there's a new loop,
وثانيهما وجود تكرار حلقي جديد،
it's called the for-of loop,
ويسمى التكرار الحلقي **for-of**،
which loops exclusively over iterable objects.
والذي يتكرر بشكل حصري حول كائنات قابلة للتكرار.
Now, when I say iterable objects,
الآن، عندما أقول كائنات قابلة للتكرار،
I just mean an object that has implemented this new iterable interface.
فإنني أقصد الكائن الذي نفَّذ الواجهة الجديدة القابلة للتكرار هذه.
See here the for and the of.
انظروا هنا إلى **for** و**of**.
Now, this might sound a little bit fuzzy.
الآن، قد يبدو هذا غامضًا بعض الشيء.
So let's actually take a step back and look at
لذلك دعونا نخطو خطوة للخلف ونلقِ نظرة على
some code examples of traditional for loops,
بعض أمثلة الأكواد لتكرارات حلقية "for" تقليدية،
and then see how the new for-of loop really stands out as your best option for looping.
ثم لنرى كيف يبدو التكرار الحلقي من الفئة **for-of** كخيارك الأفضل للتكرار